# Jacques Everiss

07576166617

Jacques.Everiss@gmail.com

GitHub.com/JEveriss

LinkedIn.com/in/Jacques-Everiss

## **Personal Summary**

I'm a frontend engineer with 2 years of experience and an enthusiasm for UX, inclusivity, and creating the right solution to solve the problem.

I've worked on both agile product teams, focussing on iterative delivery, and waterfall teams focussing on meeting tight deadlines.

# **Key Skills**

Languages & Frameworks	JavaScript - HTML - CSS - React - Next.js
Tools	GitHub - Cypress - Jira - StoryBook - Shopify - Contentful

## **Work Experience**

## Freelance Web Developer

September 2023 - Present

- Built multiple websites with headless CMSs using NextJS, Shopify, and Contentful.
- These websites have helped local companies to update their events and product information, increased their marketing capabilities, and have improved both the accessibility and performance of their websites.

#### 383 Project

Associate Frontend Engineer

June 2022 - September 2023

- Worked as part of the Hilton Hotels Product Team, contributed to new feature development, maintaining existing components, and reducing technical debt
- Updated company branding to ensure the site was consistent and adhered to current brand guidelines

- Led the development of projects including building a WordPress site to show the company's crossbrowser compatibility to clients and building a working Shopify prototype that could be demoed to clients
- · Worked as part of the Support Team for all projects within the company, handling urgent SLAs
- · Worked closely with designers, QA, and project managers to create new features
- Performed code reviews for other engineers, from junior to senior, to ensure the consistent, high level of code was contributed to the codebases
- Demoed projects to clients, the wider company, and leadership to showcase the work we had accomplished

#### Meet Bernard

Retail Store Manager

October 2020 - October 2021

- Managed two retail stores for an independent clothing boutique where I was in charge of a team of 12 staff members
- · Used analysis of sales data to assist with buying correct levels of new season stock

#### Barbour

Retail Assistant Store Manager

October 2016 - September 2020

- Reached £1 million gross profit for the first time and maintained a 2% increase year on year for the following two years
- Compiled detailed monthly sales reports to provide deeper analysis to that period of trading

## **Qualifications**

#### W3C Accessibility

Digital Accessibility Foundations Course

September 2023

 Covered the importance of creating accessible products using the semantic html elements and the wide variety in which disabilities are presented

#### School of Code

Full Stack Web Development Course

November 2021 - April 2022

- · 16 week, full time, intensive course carried out remotely
- · Completed weekly group tech tests in which we implemented the learning from the previous week

• For the final group project we designed an app to reduce food waste. Users could create an account and save food items as the contents of their "fridge". We used Heroku to store the user accounts in a database, Auth0 for authentication, and then used a free recipe API to suggest recipes based on their listed food items

## University of the Arts London

October 2011 - June 2015

Sound Arts and Design, BA hons

• For my final major project I created an electro-acoustic instrument that could be played by the gallery attendees. It included a 6 note synthesiser that I made from scratch that would change frequency based on the time of the day and a set of chimes that could produce both acoustic and electronic sound

#### **Interests**

I have been playing the drums and guitar for roughly 20 years and currently play in two bands. I previously ran my own record label for a number of years through which I co-released several records that were released internationally.

I also enjoy playing board games and the competitive card game, Magic the Gathering.

References are available upon request